{"mainPropery":{"diseaseId":8648,"diseaseName":"Desmoplastic infantile ganglioglioma","hasGardWebPage":true,"isRare":true,"websiteUrl":"https://rarediseases.info.nih.gov/diseases/8648/desmoplastic-infantile-ganglioglioma","synonyms":["DIG"],"synonyms-with-source":[{"name":"DIG"}],"identifiers":[{"identifierType":"UMLS","identifierId":"C1321878"}]},"diseaseCategories":[{"diseaseTypeId":1,"diseaseTypeName":"Rare Cancers"}],"organizations":[],"resource descriptions":[{"id":8,"resourceId":11,"resourceName":"PubMed","descriptionText":"<a href='http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/sites/entrez?Db=pubmed&Cmd=DetailsSearch&Term=desmoplastic+infantile+ganglioglioma%5Bti%5D' target='_blank'>PubMed</a> is a searchable database of medical literature and lists journal articles that discuss Desmoplastic infantile ganglioglioma. Click on the link to view a sample search on this topic.","resourceClassificationName":"Overview","resourceClassificationSectionName":"In-Depth Information"},{"id":1403,"resourceId":2053,"resourceName":"Desmoplastic Infantile Ganglioma cancer.net","descriptionText":"<a href='http://www.cancer.net/patient/Cancer+Types/Desmoplastic+Infantile+Ganglioglioma+-+Childhood ' target='_blank'>Cancer.Net</a>, oncologist-approved cancer information from the American Society of Clinical Oncology, provides information about desmoplastic infantile ganglioma. Click on the link to read this information. &nbsp;","resourceClassificationName":"Overview","resourceClassificationSectionName":"Where to Start"},{"id":1543,"resourceId":2171,"resourceName":"National Cancer Institute","descriptionText":"The <a href='http://www.cancer.gov/cancertopics/pdq/treatment/adultbrain/HealthProfessional/page1' target='_blank'>National Cancer Institute</a> provides the most current information on cancer for patients, health professionals, and the general public.<br />\r\n","resourceClassificationName":"Overview","resourceClassificationSectionName":"Where to Start"}],"overviewQuestion":{"questionId":527,"questionText":"What is desmoplastic infantile gangliomas (DIGs)?","answerText":"<strong>Desmoplastic infantile gangliomas</strong> <strong>(DIGs)</strong> are rare brain tumors that are normally located in the <a href=\"http://www.ninds.nih.gov/disorders/brain_basics/know_your_brain.htm\" target=_blank>frontal</a> or <a href=\"http://www.ninds.nih.gov/disorders/brain_basics/know_your_brain.htm\" target=_blank>parietal lobes</a> of the brain. They are usually diagnosed before 18 months of age with most infants presenting with a short duration of symptoms. Although seizures are not commonly observed, a bulging <a href=\"http://www.nlm.nih.gov/medlineplus/ency/article/003310.htm\" target=_blank>fontanelle</a>, rapid head growth, vomiting, and a <a href=\"http://mediphotos.blogspot.com/2012/01/appearance-of-sunset-sign-in-infant.html\" target=_blank>sunset sign</a> are usually noted. The standard treatment for DIGs is surgical resection (surgical procedure in which the portion of the brain with the tumor is removed).[350]","dateModified":"2013-07-30T14:32:00"},"basicQuestions":[{"questionId":531,"questionText":"What signs and symptoms are associated with desmoplastic infantile gangliomas?","answerText":"Most infants with DIGs do not have seizures; however, they usually have a bulging fontanelle, rapid head growth, sunset sign, and vomiting.[350]","dateModified":"2013-07-30T14:39:00","resourceClassificationName":"Symptoms","references":[{"referenceId":350,"authors":"Smith SH","articleTitle":"Uncommon Pediatric Brain Tumors","bookWebsiteJournalTitle":"Textbook of Uncommon Cancer. 3rd ed","date":"2006","authors2":"Raghavan D, Brecher ML, Johnson DH, Meropol NJ, Moots PL, Rose PG","placeOfPublication":"England","publisher":"John Wiley & Sons Ltd"}]},{"questionId":529,"questionText":"How are desmoplastic infantile gangliomas diagnosed?","answerText":"In addition to detecting the signs and symptoms commonly seen in DIGs, head <a href=\"http://www.nlm.nih.gov/medlineplus/ctscans.html\" target=_blank>CT scans</a> and <a href=\"http://www.nlm.nih.gov/medlineplus/mriscans.html\" target=_blank>MRIs</a> may reveal the presence of this type of brain tumor.[350]","dateModified":"2013-07-30T14:33:00","resourceClassificationName":"Diagnosis","references":[{"referenceId":350,"authors":"Smith SH","articleTitle":"Uncommon Pediatric Brain Tumors","bookWebsiteJournalTitle":"Textbook of Uncommon Cancer. 3rd ed","date":"2006","authors2":"Raghavan D, Brecher ML, Johnson DH, Meropol NJ, Moots PL, Rose PG","placeOfPublication":"England","publisher":"John Wiley & Sons Ltd"}]},{"questionId":530,"questionText":"What treatment is available for desmoplastic infantile gangliomas?","answerText":"Surgical resection (removal of the area of the brain with the tumor) has been the standard treatment reported in the medical literature. The size of the resection is probably based on the size of the tumor, although the extent of the resection is not documented for all cases reported in the medical literature. <a href=\"http://www.cancer.gov/dictionary?cdrid=45587\" target=_blank>Adjuvant therapy</a> is generally not performed when a gross total resection can be performed. When total resection is not possible, some of suggested chemotherapy, as the effects of radiation on extremely young children may be harmful.[350]","dateModified":"2013-07-30T14:37:00","resourceClassificationName":"Treatment","references":[{"referenceId":350,"authors":"Smith SH","articleTitle":"Uncommon Pediatric Brain Tumors","bookWebsiteJournalTitle":"Textbook of Uncommon Cancer. 3rd ed","date":"2006","authors2":"Raghavan D, Brecher ML, Johnson DH, Meropol NJ, Moots PL, Rose PG","placeOfPublication":"England","publisher":"John Wiley & Sons Ltd"}]},{"questionId":532,"questionText":"What prognosis is associated with desmoplastic infantile gangliogliomas?","answerText":"Follow-up has generally been favorable following complete surgical resection in the reported cases of DIGs. Spontaneous regression of the tumor following partial surgical resection has also been documented.[351]","dateModified":"2013-07-30T14:39:00","resourceClassificationName":"Prognosis","references":[{"referenceId":351,"authors":"Fadare O, Mariappan MR, Hileeto D, Zieske AW, Kim JH, Ocal IT","articleTitle":"Desmoplastidc Infantile Ganglioglioma:  cytologic findings and differential diagnosis on aspiration material","bookWebsiteJournalTitle":"CytoJournal","date":"11 January 2005"}]}],"references":[],"relatedDiseases":[],"gardCases":[{"caseId":21465,"abbreviatedInquiry":"My son has been diagnosed with a desmoplastic infantile ganglioma? Could you tell me more about this tumor.","caseQuestions":[{"questionId":527,"questionText":"What is desmoplastic infantile gangliomas (DIGs)?","answerText":"<strong>Desmoplastic infantile gangliomas</strong> <strong>(DIGs)</strong> are rare brain tumors that are normally located in the <a href=\"http://www.ninds.nih.gov/disorders/brain_basics/know_your_brain.htm\" target=_blank>frontal</a> or <a href=\"http://www.ninds.nih.gov/disorders/brain_basics/know_your_brain.htm\" target=_blank>parietal lobes</a> of the brain. They are usually diagnosed before 18 months of age with most infants presenting with a short duration of symptoms. Although seizures are not commonly observed, a bulging <a href=\"http://www.nlm.nih.gov/medlineplus/ency/article/003310.htm\" target=_blank>fontanelle</a>, rapid head growth, vomiting, and a <a href=\"http://mediphotos.blogspot.com/2012/01/appearance-of-sunset-sign-in-infant.html\" target=_blank>sunset sign</a> are usually noted. The standard treatment for DIGs is surgical resection (surgical procedure in which the portion of the brain with the tumor is removed).[350]","dateModified":"2013-07-30T14:32:00","references":[{"referenceId":350,"authors":"Smith SH","articleTitle":"Uncommon Pediatric Brain Tumors","bookWebsiteJournalTitle":"Textbook of Uncommon Cancer. 3rd ed","date":"2006","authors2":"Raghavan D, Brecher ML, Johnson DH, Meropol NJ, Moots PL, Rose PG","placeOfPublication":"England","publisher":"John Wiley & Sons Ltd"}]},{"questionId":531,"questionText":"What signs and symptoms are associated with desmoplastic infantile gangliomas?","answerText":"Most infants with DIGs do not have seizures; however, they usually have a bulging fontanelle, rapid head growth, sunset sign, and vomiting.[350]","dateModified":"2013-07-30T14:39:00","resourceClassificationName":"Symptoms","references":[{"referenceId":350,"authors":"Smith SH","articleTitle":"Uncommon Pediatric Brain Tumors","bookWebsiteJournalTitle":"Textbook of Uncommon Cancer. 3rd ed","date":"2006","authors2":"Raghavan D, Brecher ML, Johnson DH, Meropol NJ, Moots PL, Rose PG","placeOfPublication":"England","publisher":"John Wiley & Sons Ltd"}]},{"questionId":529,"questionText":"How are desmoplastic infantile gangliomas diagnosed?","answerText":"In addition to detecting the signs and symptoms commonly seen in DIGs, head <a href=\"http://www.nlm.nih.gov/medlineplus/ctscans.html\" target=_blank>CT scans</a> and <a href=\"http://www.nlm.nih.gov/medlineplus/mriscans.html\" target=_blank>MRIs</a> may reveal the presence of this type of brain tumor.[350]","dateModified":"2013-07-30T14:33:00","resourceClassificationName":"Diagnosis","references":[{"referenceId":350,"authors":"Smith SH","articleTitle":"Uncommon Pediatric Brain Tumors","bookWebsiteJournalTitle":"Textbook of Uncommon Cancer. 3rd ed","date":"2006","authors2":"Raghavan D, Brecher ML, Johnson DH, Meropol NJ, Moots PL, Rose PG","placeOfPublication":"England","publisher":"John Wiley & Sons Ltd"}]},{"questionId":530,"questionText":"What treatment is available for desmoplastic infantile gangliomas?","answerText":"Surgical resection (removal of the area of the brain with the tumor) has been the standard treatment reported in the medical literature. The size of the resection is probably based on the size of the tumor, although the extent of the resection is not documented for all cases reported in the medical literature. <a href=\"http://www.cancer.gov/dictionary?cdrid=45587\" target=_blank>Adjuvant therapy</a> is generally not performed when a gross total resection can be performed. When total resection is not possible, some of suggested chemotherapy, as the effects of radiation on extremely young children may be harmful.[350]","dateModified":"2013-07-30T14:37:00","resourceClassificationName":"Treatment","references":[{"referenceId":350,"authors":"Smith SH","articleTitle":"Uncommon Pediatric Brain Tumors","bookWebsiteJournalTitle":"Textbook of Uncommon Cancer. 3rd ed","date":"2006","authors2":"Raghavan D, Brecher ML, Johnson DH, Meropol NJ, Moots PL, Rose PG","placeOfPublication":"England","publisher":"John Wiley & Sons Ltd"}]},{"questionId":532,"questionText":"What prognosis is associated with desmoplastic infantile gangliogliomas?","answerText":"Follow-up has generally been favorable following complete surgical resection in the reported cases of DIGs. Spontaneous regression of the tumor following partial surgical resection has also been documented.[351]","dateModified":"2013-07-30T14:39:00","resourceClassificationName":"Prognosis","references":[{"referenceId":351,"authors":"Fadare O, Mariappan MR, Hileeto D, Zieske AW, Kim JH, Ocal IT","articleTitle":"Desmoplastidc Infantile Ganglioglioma:  cytologic findings and differential diagnosis on aspiration material","bookWebsiteJournalTitle":"CytoJournal","date":"11 January 2005"}]}]}],"news":[{"newsId":671,"dateCreated":"2020-05-20T13:39:00","publishDate":"2020-05-22T00:00:00","title":"NIH-Supported Research Survey to Examine Impact of COVID-19 on Rare Diseases Community","description":"The NIH-funded Rare Diseases Clinical Research Network (RDCRN) has launched an <a href=\"https://www.rarediseasesnetwork.org/COVIDsurvey \" target=\"_blank\">online research survey</a> to find out how the COVID-19 pandemic is impacting individuals with rare diseases, their families and their caregivers. Your participation can help the rare disease research community shed light on the needs of people with rare diseases during this and other potential health crises, in addition to informing future research efforts. The survey must be completed by December 15, 2020.","url":"https://www.rarediseasesnetwork.org/COVIDsurvey","lastModified":"2020-11-30T14:44:00","isFeatured":false}],"conferences":[],"phenoTypes":[],"medicalProducts":[],"EncodedName":"Desmoplastic_infantile_ganglioglioma"}